around the world renewable energy use is
on the rise and these alternative energy
sources could hold the key to combating
climate change what is renewable energy
renewable energy is generated from
sources that naturally replenish
themselves and never run out the most
common sources are solar wind hydro
geothermal and biomass over 80% of the
total energy consumed by humans is
derived from fossil fuels
however renewables are the fastest
growing source of energy in the world
renewable energy has many benefits first
it can combat climate change because it
creates no direct greenhouse gas
emissions the only emissions that they
produce are indirect meaning those that
result from manufacturing parts
installation operation and maintenance
but even those are minimal second
renewable energy can decrease pollution
and therefore reduce threats to our
health wind solar and hydroelectric
systems create no air pollution
emissions and geothermal and biomass
energy systems emissions are much lower
than non-renewable energy sources
third renewable energy is a reliable
source of power because renewable energy
sources are well renewable they will
never run out once built renewable
facilities cost very little to operate
and the fuel is often free as a result
renewable energy prices tend to be
stable over time while renewable energy
has many advantages it is not without
downsides it is difficult for renewable
energy sources to generate power on the
same large scale as fossil fuels
building wind farms and dams can disrupt
wildlife and migration patterns and lead
to ecological destruction both solar and
wind energy are intermittent they only
generate power while the sun is shining
or while the wind is blowing batteries
can store excess energy for later use
however they are often costly while
renewable energy presents some
challenges
it also offers an environmentally
friendly alternative to the greenhouse
gas emissions and pollution of fossil
fuels
and as advances in technology make
renewable energy more accessible
affordable and efficient an end to
climate change could be within our reach
[Music]